<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Matias Andina</title>
    <link>/tags/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Matias Andina</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>matiasandina@gmail.com (Matias Andina)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>matiasandina@gmail.com (Matias Andina)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing challenge Day 1</title>
      <link>/2018/08/writing-challenge-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>matiasandina@gmail.com (Matias Andina)</author>
      <guid>/2018/08/writing-challenge-day-1/</guid>
      <description>Writing ChallengeIt’s been a while since I have several things to write in the back of my mind. I finally got the will to commit myself to one of those goal oriented challenges: Writing 2000 words a day.
It might sound like a bit much, now that I think about it, but today is Day 1 so I might as well get to do it. I have not limited the type of content I will write, my aim is to get as fluent as possible and to have writing become habitual.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Github style calendar heatmaps</title>
      <link>/2018/05/github-style-calendar-heatmaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>matiasandina@gmail.com (Matias Andina)</author>
      <guid>/2018/05/github-style-calendar-heatmaps/</guid>
      <description>I like how the commit heatmap looks in Github. I wanted to play with something that could be plotted that way. I’ve seen some beautiful things done in d3 and javascript. But, of course, I wanted to make it in R. Turns out a bunch of other people have great ideas for how to go about it. Thus, I’m borrowing heavily from them1.
library(ggplot2)library(dplyr)library(lubridate)library(viridis) # Color palettelibrary(ggthemes) # theme tufteLet’s generate a data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making atlas images</title>
      <link>/2018/05/making-atlas-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>matiasandina@gmail.com (Matias Andina)</author>
      <guid>/2018/05/making-atlas-images/</guid>
      <description>This post contains a quick description/recipe for making vectorial brain atlas images suitable for publication and presentations. This post is as much for communication as for personal records.
Step 1 - The atlas itself Starting material should be as good quality as possible. I used .eps files from Paxinos Rat Brain Atlas for doing this. On the cheap side of life, a very nice online resource can be found here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning and Memory</title>
      <link>/page/learning-and-memory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>matiasandina@gmail.com (Matias Andina)</author>
      <guid>/page/learning-and-memory/</guid>
      <description>In Argentina, my research was focused in Contextual Pavlovian Conditioning of the crab Neohelice granulata. The original paradigm was thoroughly described by Fustiñana et al., 2013. We were able to expand this paradigm and unveil new unexpected long-term memories. Working in the Neurobiology of the Memory Lab has been a fulfilling experience. My research was materialized in my graduation thesis:
“Study of different long-term memories and participation of synaptic ERK/MAPK in memory consolidation”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maternal Behavior</title>
      <link>/page/maternal-behavior/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>matiasandina@gmail.com (Matias Andina)</author>
      <guid>/page/maternal-behavior/</guid>
      <description>During my time in the University of Massachusetts Amherst I studied maternal behavior in rats. I learned several new techniques and had my first experience working with rodents (actually switched from invertebrates to vertebrates!).
This work materialized in my MSc. thesis: Mapping a pup-resposive pathway from medial preoptic area to ventral tegmental area.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a nice picture of the mPOA with triple labelling: Fluorogold (yellow), Esr1 (red), c-Fos (white).
  Immunohistochemistry in mPOA</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>