<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Matias Andina</title>
    <link>/tags/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Matias Andina</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>matiasandina@gmail.com (Matias Andina)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>matiasandina@gmail.com (Matias Andina)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Skype a Scientist part 1</title>
      <link>/2018/10/skype-a-scientist-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>matiasandina@gmail.com (Matias Andina)</author>
      <guid>/2018/10/skype-a-scientist-part-1/</guid>
      <description>I have been lucky to participate in the project lead by Sarah McAnultycalled Skype a scientist. So far, I have done calls with two grades:
3rd Grade Johnston Elementary School, Irving, TX.7th Grade Isbell Middle School, Santa Paula, CA.I should say it was great to be able to talk with students, tell them about science in general and my research. It was really fun to answer their questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing challenge day 28</title>
      <link>/2018/09/writing-challenge-day-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>matiasandina@gmail.com (Matias Andina)</author>
      <guid>/2018/09/writing-challenge-day-28/</guid>
      <description>This month has been fast. The writing has been really interesting, I was able to get some old stories written and had a lot of fun doing it. I would like to continue with the habit, it is already making it easier for me to put words into text. I’m not sure about the quality, but I experience the writing ease for both Spanish and English.
The dataI had some pretty long bouts on Saturday and Sunday, writing close to 3000 words in aggregate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing challenge Day 21</title>
      <link>/2018/09/writing-challenge-day-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>matiasandina@gmail.com (Matias Andina)</author>
      <guid>/2018/09/writing-challenge-day-21/</guid>
      <description>Third week has had ups and downs. I finished another short story. But I keep losing the word count battle. Yes, again, work.
The dataThe word count data is somewhat similar to what I’ve seen for last week. Definitely writing bouts are going down, just being able to write a few words before bedtime knocks me over.
Looking at the aggregate, the downward slope of the third week is a little bit disappointing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing challenge Day 14</title>
      <link>/2018/09/writing-challenge-day-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>matiasandina@gmail.com (Matias Andina)</author>
      <guid>/2018/09/writing-challenge-day-14/</guid>
      <description>During the second week of the challenge I had a lot of late working days. It has been certainly tiresome. As a consequence, I was less able to write, got home really tired.
I still have that voice powering my desire to write. Actually, over the weekend I finished a short story that I had in my list for at least a year. That achievement feels really good and pumps the desire to keep writing and, most importantly, finishing more projects than those I start.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing challenge Day 1</title>
      <link>/2018/08/writing-challenge-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>matiasandina@gmail.com (Matias Andina)</author>
      <guid>/2018/08/writing-challenge-day-1/</guid>
      <description>It’s been a while since I have several things to write in the back of my mind. I finally got the will to commit myself to one of those goal oriented challenges: Writing 2000 words a day.
It might sound like a bit much, now that I think about it, but today is Day 1 so I might as well get to do it. I have not limited the type of content I will write, my aim is to get as fluent as possible and to have writing become habitual.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Github style calendar heatmaps</title>
      <link>/2018/05/github-style-calendar-heatmaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>matiasandina@gmail.com (Matias Andina)</author>
      <guid>/2018/05/github-style-calendar-heatmaps/</guid>
      <description>I like how the commit heatmap looks in Github. I wanted to play with something that could be plotted that way. I’ve seen some beautiful things done in d3 and javascript. But, of course, I wanted to make it in R. Turns out a bunch of other people have great ideas for how to go about it. Thus, I’m borrowing heavily from them1.
library(ggplot2)library(dplyr)library(lubridate)library(viridis) # Color palettelibrary(ggthemes) # theme tufteLet’s generate a data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making atlas images</title>
      <link>/2018/05/making-atlas-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>matiasandina@gmail.com (Matias Andina)</author>
      <guid>/2018/05/making-atlas-images/</guid>
      <description>This post contains a quick description/recipe for making vectorial brain atlas images suitable for publication and presentations. This post is as much for communication as for personal records.
Step 1 - The atlas itself Starting material should be as good quality as possible. I used .eps files from Paxinos Rat Brain Atlas for doing this. On the cheap side of life, a very nice online resource can be found here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning and Memory</title>
      <link>/page/learning-and-memory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>matiasandina@gmail.com (Matias Andina)</author>
      <guid>/page/learning-and-memory/</guid>
      <description>In Argentina, my research was focused in Contextual Pavlovian Conditioning of the crab Neohelice granulata. The original paradigm was thoroughly described by Fustiñana et al., 2013. We were able to expand this paradigm and unveil new unexpected long-term memories. Working in the Neurobiology of the Memory Lab has been a fulfilling experience. My research was materialized in my graduation thesis:
“Study of different long-term memories and participation of synaptic ERK/MAPK in memory consolidation”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maternal Behavior</title>
      <link>/page/maternal-behavior/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>matiasandina@gmail.com (Matias Andina)</author>
      <guid>/page/maternal-behavior/</guid>
      <description>During my time in the University of Massachusetts Amherst I studied maternal behavior in rats. I learned several new techniques and had my first experience working with rodents (actually switched from invertebrates to vertebrates!).
Rat pup of around 12 days old.
 Here&amp;rsquo;s a nice picture of mPOA neurons with triple labelling: VTA-projecting (Fluorogold, yellow), Esr1 (red), c-Fos (white).
Immunohistochemistry in mPOA</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>