<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Teaching on Matias Andina</title>
    <link>/tags/teaching/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Teaching on Matias Andina</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>matiasandina@gmail.com (Matias Andina)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>matiasandina@gmail.com (Matias Andina)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/teaching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About student motivation</title>
      <link>/2017/12/about-student-motivation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>matiasandina@gmail.com (Matias Andina)</author>
      <guid>/2017/12/about-student-motivation/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m writing this post to document my own learning on reading from Teaching Tips and Teaching at its Best.
I have found chapter 11 of McKeachie&amp;rsquo;s to be of great value, it contains lots of starting points for discussion and further analysis.
Choice Humans are into the free will thing. Access to choosing their own topic, exam questions and due dates might facilitate the learning experience and boost motivation through a feeling of agency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About grades</title>
      <link>/2017/12/about-grades/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>matiasandina@gmail.com (Matias Andina)</author>
      <guid>/2017/12/about-grades/</guid>
      <description>I’m writing this post to document my own learning on reading from Teaching Tips and Teaching at its Best.
Calibrated instrumentsMcKeachie’s chapter 10 starts with a set of questions that attack the problem of grading from a philosophical angle.
what are grades?
First define the problem (What is the system? What are the governing rules?). Do we agree that grades are communication tools? That is an extremely challenging and insightful question.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List of Common Errors</title>
      <link>/2017/12/list-of-common-errors/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>matiasandina@gmail.com (Matias Andina)</author>
      <guid>/2017/12/list-of-common-errors/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m writing this post to document my own learning on reading from Teaching Tips and Teaching at its Best.
Assignments and Feedback Chapters 7 and 8 on McKeachie&amp;rsquo;s Teaching tips are quite interesting and develop different lines of thought about assignments. One thing I can relate to is the idea of providing general examples of errors students normally do. This procedure comes handy when dealing with essay questions (the ones I like far more than any other).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Any Questions?</title>
      <link>/2017/12/any-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>matiasandina@gmail.com (Matias Andina)</author>
      <guid>/2017/12/any-questions/</guid>
      <description>I’m writing this post to document my own learning on reading from Teaching Tips and Teaching at its Best. This particular post has to do with engaging students to contribute with questions to class.
Checking student understandingDuring class, there is a moment in which you feel that you’ve covered a couple of ideas in the way you wanted to and you decide to check if everything is alright. Other times, you feel as if you weren’t able to convey the points in the way you wanted to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Teaching Nonsense</title>
      <link>/2017/11/about-teaching-nonsense/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>matiasandina@gmail.com (Matias Andina)</author>
      <guid>/2017/11/about-teaching-nonsense/</guid>
      <description>Life without purposeLiving without a purpose is something I am unable to do. I am into the rules of the game, the idea that there’s a goal, and we are trying to achieve something, do something, create an object or service that was not there before and now fulfills a function. There are few games that I play for the sake of keep playing like the learning game. But, more often than not, I stand on the side of finite games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do you make a cake?</title>
      <link>/2017/11/how-do-you-make-a-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>matiasandina@gmail.com (Matias Andina)</author>
      <guid>/2017/11/how-do-you-make-a-cake/</guid>
      <description>This post is inspired by my brief experience with the education system in the United States (US) and the way some students approach learning. I do not know what it is. Maybe it has to do with the tsunami of multiple-choice exams they have to go through, or the endless preparation for another standardized test on the horizon, or the glorification of the take-home message culture.
I wrote a question for an assignment that was pointing towards mechanisms at the level of the synapse that could result in drug tolerance.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>