<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>design on Matias Andina</title>
    <link>/tags/design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in design on Matias Andina</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Queen&#39;s Gambit</title>
      <link>/2021/02/queens-gambit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/02/queens-gambit/</guid>
      <description>I love games. I enjoy the fun in many formats: cards, boards, consoles. Yet, over the years, chess has consolidated as the game I play most often, and it is likely the only game I both really like and can limit the amount I play1.
It&amp;rsquo;s been a couple of months since I noticed something weird going on, a sort of disturbance in the force. I felt I was playing a type of position called Queen&amp;rsquo;s Gambit way more often than normal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Github style calendar heatmaps</title>
      <link>/2018/05/github-style-calendar-heatmaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/github-style-calendar-heatmaps/</guid>
      <description>I like how the commit heatmap looks in Github. I wanted to play with something that could be plotted that way. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen some beautiful things done in d3 and javascript. But, of course, I wanted to make it in R. Turns out a bunch of other people have great ideas for how to go about it. Thus, I&amp;rsquo;m borrowing heavily from them1.
library(ggplot2) library(dplyr) library(lubridate) library(viridis) # Color palette library(ggthemes) # theme tufte  Let&amp;rsquo;s generate a data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making atlas images</title>
      <link>/2018/05/making-atlas-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/making-atlas-images/</guid>
      <description>This post contains a quick description/recipe for making vectorial brain atlas images suitable for publication and presentations. This post is as much for communication as for personal records.
Step 1 - The atlas itself Starting material should be as good quality as possible. I used .eps files from Paxinos Rat Brain Atlas for doing this. On the cheap side of life, a very nice online resource can be found here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>