<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Matias Andina</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Matias Andina</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On pipelines</title>
      <link>/post/2019-11-14-on-pipelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-11-14-on-pipelines/</guid>
      <description>I have been thinking about different problems I have when writing code and the things that I normally try to do to keep my projects clean and functional. I wrote this post to put this thoughts out there, hopefully I will receive input from the great software engineers out there.
 I write fiction and non-fiction. I write open-source software. I create generative art.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skype a Scientist part 2</title>
      <link>/post/2019-09-13-skype-a-scientist-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-09-13-skype-a-scientist-2/</guid>
      <description>I have been lucky to participate in the project lead by Sarah McAnulty called Skype a scientist. I recently did two more calls with 11th grade students who attend Dowal school in Honduras. This was the first time I did Skype a Scientist in Spanish!
As usual, I should say it was great to be able to talk with students, tell them about science in general and my research. It was really fun to answer their questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Los mismos de siempre</title>
      <link>/post/2019-09-10-los-mismos-de-siempre/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-09-10-los-mismos-de-siempre/</guid>
      <description>Hace rato que vengo viendo ciertas tendencias de gente que hace algo de análisis de datos con la actualidad Argentina. Por ejemplo, Daniel Schteingart comúnmente publica este tipo de análisis en diversos medios. Esto me llevó a buscar datos abiertos disponibles para jugar un rato.
En general, a mí me interesa más debatir sobre la implementación de políticas y pienso que el Poder Legislativo merece mayor atención. Siento que sobrestimamos (para bien y para mal) el poder de un Ejecutivo que es, al final del día, mucho menos determinante que aquellos que escriben las leyes según las cuales se rige el Estado.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Birthday Meritocracy</title>
      <link>/post/2019-05-09-birthday-meritocracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-05-09-birthday-meritocracy/</guid>
      <description>We believe in meritocracy as one of the cornerstones of Western civilization. This idea is so embedded in our culture that we seldom question it. We praise those driven individuals who combine effort and talent to make it to the top. They smile in the cover of the magazines, the dreams of children and the nightmares of adults. Sports might be the activity where the blood, sweat and tears feel most real (maybe I should say relatable) and therefore are most notoriously broadcasted to the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Visualization Challenge 2</title>
      <link>/post/2019-04-14-data-visualization-challenge-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-04-14-data-visualization-challenge-2/</guid>
      <description>This post is made as a backup for the data visualization challenge number 2. Data comes from the daily posts of the members of the Data Visualization Society (DVS) on the DVS Slack channels. You can see everybody’s submissions for the challenge here.
I am also very motivated to explore the dark versions of the ggplot themes. The package I’m going to be using is called ggdark.
 I write fiction and non-fiction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Email analysis</title>
      <link>/post/2019-04-06-email-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-04-06-email-analysis/</guid>
      <description>I am keen on tracking things. Some people call this personal analytics, I call it fun. In this post, I will explore how to extract your email information using python and R. My goal is to do some analysis on the data and, hopefully, explore different visualizations that can inform future behavior.
 I write fiction and non-fiction. I write open-source software. I create generative art. All of these are available for free in different media.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R pipeline -- It&#39;s a trap!</title>
      <link>/post/2019-02-01-r-pipeline-its-a-trap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-02-01-r-pipeline-its-a-trap/</guid>
      <description>Here’s how the story usually goes. It starts with you, sitting in front of the computer screen, thinking: What a lovely day for some data analysis!. This day is great because you have collected some data or maybe because you happened to find some data somewhere, begging to be part of a smoking good plot.
 I write fiction and non-fiction. I write open-source software. I create generative art. All of these are available for free in different media.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Query Pubmed in R</title>
      <link>/post/2018-11-23-query-pubmed-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-11-23-query-pubmed-in-r/</guid>
      <description>I have seen a couple of presentations that use plots of PubMed query results. I have even seen some of them in papers. I just think it’s really cool, so I wanted to play with something that could provide the data.
A couple of google searches lead me into two nice options to do this in R.
RISmed package, see CRAN or Dave Tang’s Blog A custom approach from Kristoffer Magnusson  I went with the custom approach, decided to borrow heavily from Kristoffer’s repo, and did a few modifications here and there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skype a Scientist part 1</title>
      <link>/post/2018-10-02-skype-a-scientist-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-10-02-skype-a-scientist-1/</guid>
      <description>I have been lucky to participate in the project lead by Sarah McAnulty called Skype a scientist. So far, I have done calls with two grades:
 3rd Grade Johnston Elementary School, Irving, TX. 7th Grade Isbell Middle School, Santa Paula, CA.  I should say it was great to be able to talk with students, tell them about science in general and my research. It was really fun to answer their questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing challenge day 28</title>
      <link>/post/2018-09-27-writing-challenge-day-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-09-27-writing-challenge-day-28/</guid>
      <description>This month has been fast. The writing has been really interesting, I was able to get some old stories written and had a lot of fun doing it. I would like to continue with the habit, it is already making it easier for me to put words into text. I’m not sure about the quality, but I experience the writing ease for both Spanish and English.
The data I had some pretty long bouts on Saturday and Sunday, writing close to 3000 words in aggregate.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>