<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Matias Andina</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Matias Andina</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Birthday Problem</title>
      <link>/2020/06/birthday-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/birthday-problem/</guid>
      <description>We have all been there, classic math riddle:
 How many people need to be in one room so that the probability of two of them having the same birthday is more than 0.5?
 In a recent bootcamp exercise we tackled this in python and I wanted to share, just because it’s fun. I did it for a range of probabilities. My solution is probably not the fastest/shortest/most pythonic, but it’s a little thing I put out there so, if you want to use/improve it, please do!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Keylogger</title>
      <link>/2020/06/python-keylogger/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/python-keylogger/</guid>
      <description>I have been struggling a lot with pain in my fingers and wrists. I have tried setting up timers for using the keyboard. But the only thing that seems to work is reducing the typing (aka get away from the computer and stop using the keyboard!).
Tracking hours didn’t work well, so I guess a last resort to force me is counting the actual number of keys per day and trying to keep that to a minimum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complex Fun</title>
      <link>/2020/04/complex-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/04/complex-fun/</guid>
      <description>People say that if you have to explain a joke, it loses value. Probably true. I guess I just wanted to partially comment on how different disciplines analyze different levels of complexity.
As molecular biologist, I think we were trained to seldom think about the whole system, we were trained to just give up complexity and focus on a couple of fancy names (yes, YFG fits pretty well as the center of this Universe).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The power of compounding</title>
      <link>/2020/01/the-power-of-compounding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/the-power-of-compounding/</guid>
      <description>Paying attention to the small details sounds like a waste of time. Where&amp;rsquo;s that 80&amp;frasl;20 rule when I need it? Well, yes, talking about a small increment sounds boring and useless. A 1% increase in performance might seem trivial. Unexciting. A rounding error.
But it is often neglected because we don&amp;rsquo;t have a good dimension of scales (e.g., A small percent of a lot of money it&amp;rsquo;s a lot of money) or even when we do, we fail to grasp what exponential phenomena look like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Escribiendo en pocas palabras</title>
      <link>/2020/01/escribiendo-en-pocas-palabras/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/escribiendo-en-pocas-palabras/</guid>
      <description>Lo bueno, si breve, dos veces bueno.
 Me tomo la libertad de este juego literario1 para introducir un ensayo con algunas pautas interesantes para escribir. En pocas palabras, Paul Graham nos regala una lista de acciones que es conveniente tomar para producir escritos de calidad.
La siguiente es una traduccion del ensayo “Writing, Briefly” escrito por Paul Graham2.
Escribir, en pocas palabras (En el proceso de responder un email, accidentalmente escribí un pequeño ensayo sobre cómo escribir.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Checklist</title>
      <link>/2020/01/writing-checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/writing-checklist/</guid>
      <description>I spent a good portion of the end of 2019 and the beginning of 2020 reading Paul Graham’s essays. Many caught my attention (and my fingers to take notes). I want to comment on an essay about advice for good writing. Because it was written in a way that allowed for easy reformatting (ideas separated by ;, I thought it would be cool to convert the prose into a checklist).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fitbit Analysis</title>
      <link>/2019/11/fitbit-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/11/fitbit-analysis/</guid>
      <description>It’s been a bit more than a year since I got a fitbit and I have been pretty excited about tracking my activity and heart rate. I should say I’m quite surprised about the sleep data. Tracking sleep has been, in fact, the most exciting feature, and I now strive to get at least 7 hours of sleep per night.
 I write fiction and non-fiction. I write open-source software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On pipelines</title>
      <link>/2019/11/on-pipelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/11/on-pipelines/</guid>
      <description>I have been thinking about different problems I have when writing code and the things that I normally try to do to keep my projects clean and functional. I wrote this post to put this thoughts out there, hopefully I will receive input from the great software engineers out there.
 I write fiction and non-fiction. I write open-source software. I create generative art.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skype a Scientist part 2</title>
      <link>/2019/09/skype-a-scientist-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/09/skype-a-scientist-part-2/</guid>
      <description>I have been lucky to participate in the project lead by Sarah McAnulty called Skype a scientist. I recently did two more calls with 11th grade students who attend Dowal school in Honduras. This was the first time I did Skype a Scientist in Spanish!
As usual, I should say it was great to be able to talk with students, tell them about science in general and my research. It was really fun to answer their questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Los mismos de siempre</title>
      <link>/2019/09/los-mismos-de-siempre/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/09/los-mismos-de-siempre/</guid>
      <description>Hace rato que vengo viendo ciertas tendencias de gente que hace algo de análisis de datos con la actualidad Argentina. Por ejemplo, Daniel Schteingart comúnmente publica este tipo de análisis en diversos medios. Esto me llevó a buscar datos abiertos disponibles para jugar un rato.
En general, a mí me interesa más debatir sobre la implementación de políticas y pienso que el Poder Legislativo merece mayor atención. Siento que sobrestimamos (para bien y para mal) el poder de un Ejecutivo que es, al final del día, mucho menos determinante que aquellos que escriben las leyes según las cuales se rige el Estado.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>